spout.com 2007-12-10

# Spout - Privacy

**Our Privacy Notice**

At SpoutSM, we’re dedicated to protecting your privacy on line.  This policy explains how we do so, and it governs your use of our site.

 **Collecting and Using Information**

We obtain information about you in a couple of different ways.  First, you give us information anytime you search, buy, post, participate, and otherwise communicate through our site. Second, we receive information about you from other sources, such as by updated delivery and address information from our carriers, information obtained through search term and search result information, and credit history information obtained from credit bureaus that help us detect and prevent fraud.  We collect and gather information, however, that is necessary or relevant for our business purposes.  We reserve the right to collect such information, either on an individual or aggregate basis. 

We will use the information we gather for business purposes.  You agree that we may do so, in our discretion, and that we are not liable in any way for such use.  (Please review our other liability limitations in our policies).  Please note that we do not share personal information we learn about you from your use of our site with others except as described in this policy.

It is not our business to sell your information to others. Further, we do not share your information with unrelated third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  We may, however, share information with our business partners in order to provide you with goods and services.  For example, if you purchase goods through this website, like any other retailer we will provide your credit card information to our credit card processor and authenticator for payment purposes, and your name and address to the company that ships our merchandise.  We may use contractors to help us collect information to run our site or provide other on-line services.  We will share data with our business partners for these purposes only upon terms that prohibit them from making any independent commercial use of individually identifiable information and that prohibit them from sharing the data with third parties or otherwise making it publicly available.  We also reserve the right to license or sell aggregate information about the visitors to our website, but this information is not individually identifiable.

We may release personal and account information without prior notice when we believe it is appropriate to prevent fraud; to comply with law or to cooperate with law enforcement activity or other governmental request; to respond to subpoenas, court orders or administrative agency requests for information; to enforce our policies; and to protect the rights, property and safety of our business and of others.  If we ever sell the company, division or business unit that operates this site, we may also transfer the information we have collected in connection with such sale or merger.

We will use the information we collect to continuously improve our business and our website development.  Your comments and suggestions about our website development are always appreciated.  You can provide us with your comments by contacting us.  
  
 **Changes to Your Preferences and Information**

The information you provide us isn’t set in stone. You can edit your account information with us at any time. Most personal information you may provide is entirely optional. You can modify your account by visiting the applicable account pages or delete your account by contacting us. However, please note that some personal information, primarily your contact information, may remain in our records to the extent necessary to protect our legal or business interests. 

**Cookies**

You’ve heard about “cookies,” but in the web-world, these aren’t something you can nibble on with a glass of milk. A “cookie” is a small amount of data (think of a chocolate chip) that often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive (“cookies in the cupboard”).  Like many web sites, we use “cookies” or similar technology to make our site easier to use.

You can manage these cookies. For example, you can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set.  Please keep the following in mind when you do this, however:

> •    If you reject all cookies, you may not be able to use parts of our site that require you to "sign in," and you may not be able to take full advantage of Spout’s offerings.  
> •    We may use our own cookie collection for a number of purposes, including:   
> 
>
>> o    Requiring you to re-enter your password after a certain period of time has elapsed to protect you against others accidentally accessing your account contents;  
> o    Keeping track of preferences you specify while you are using our site;  
> o    Estimating and reporting our total audience size and traffic.  
> o    Conducting research to improve the content and services provided on our site.   
> 
> 
> •    We may allow other persons and parties to display advertisements on our web pages and sometimes these folks will set and access their cookies on your computer. Other entities' use of cookies is the subject to their privacy policies and not of this policy. We keep the hands of advertisers or other entities out of our “cookie” jar, so they do not have access to our cookies.   
> 

**Children**

Our site is geared to people age 18 or older. We do not sell products for purchase by children. We do sell children’s products for purchase by adults.  If you are under the age of 18, you may use our site, but only with the involvement of a parent or guardian. 

**Confidentiality & Security**

No activity on the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  We cannot, therefore, guarantee the security of any information that you transmit and you make such transmissions at your own risk.  Once we receive your transmission, however, we make efforts to ensure security on our systems, by the following:

> •    We use physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information.  
> •    Your account information is password-protected.  
> •    We may use industry-standard SSL-encryption to protect data transmissions. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software.   
> 

We cannot provide absolute assurances against, and will not be liable for, breaches of confidentiality due to system failures or unauthorized access by third parties.

If we learn about a security systems breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using our site or providing personal information to us you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of those sites, products and services. We may post a notice on our site if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the applicable web sites. We may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us. Contact Us.  
  
 **Changes to This Policy**

The world of on-line business is constantly changing.  To keep up with and account for these changes, we may occasionally revise or update this policy. Please keep your eye on this policy in the event such changes are made.  Scout.com will send a message to the primary e-mail address we have on file for you if we make a change, or post a prominent notice of the change on the site.

 **Contacting Us**

If you have any privacy concerns about our site or its policies, please contact us by email. Contact Us.

Back to top
